

## **RESUME**

Name: Nilesh

## Summary:

Total 9 years of experience in software development with an urge to learn new innovative skills and technologies. Ability to work in a group as well as individual and good in handling function pertaining analysis, development and testing.

2 year relative experience in Xamarin mobile application development.

## **Objective:**

Seeking a position to utilize my skills and abilities in the industry that offers professional growth while being resourceful, innovative and flexible in contribution to organization goals.

Educational Qualification:				
Degree	College	University	Year	Percentage
A.C.E.D ( Aptech Certified E-Commerce Developer)	Aptech Computer Education, Shivajinagar, Pune	Aptech	2005	84%
H.D.S.E ( Higher Diploma In Software Engineering )	Aptech Computer Education, Shivajinagar, Pune	Aptech	2003	80%
B. Com	Bharatiya Jain Sanghatana College Wagholi, Pune	Pune	2001	52%
H.S.C	V. S. Satav College, Wagholi, Pune	Maharashtra Board	1998	62.50%
S.S.C	V. S. Satav Highschool, Wagholi, Pune	Maharashtra Board	1996	65.64%

Computer Skills:	
Language:	.NET MVC 3 & 4, ASP.net, WPF, WCF, C#, VB.Net, Visual Basic 6.0
Web Technologies:	HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS, Jquery, Ajax, XML, Bootstrap theme.
Javascript MVC framework	AngularJs
Databases:	SQL Server 2008 R2, MySQL, MS Access
NoSql Databases	MongoDB
CMS Web tool	Orchard CMS 1.6
Payment gateway	Fiserv, Govolution's Velocity Payment System, Payu money, PayPal
Repository Tool	VisualSVN, GitHub, Bitbucket (SourceTree tool), TFS and VSTS
Native Mobile Framework	Xamarin (Xamarin.iOS, Xamarin.Android,Xamarin.Forms)
Project Mangemnet Tool	JIRA, EasyProjects, Rally
0.S.:	Windows 2007 and Windows 2008, Window 8/8.1, Windows 10
Report Tool:	Crystal Report, SSRS



Professional Experience:		
Company	Duration	Current Role/Position
iWork Technologies Pvt. Ltd.	July 2011 – till date	Team Lead and technical architect
Deccan Mechanical	Sept 2007- July 2011	Programmer

### **PROJECTS**

#1. Groupix chat mobile application (iOS,Android)	
Client Name:	Xpanxion International pvt. ltd.
Team Size:	1
Duration:	May 2016 to Aug 2016
Technologies:	Xamarin.iOS, Xamarin.Android, Quickblox framework, C#

### Description:

It is group chat Mobile application for iOS and Android. User can communicate within group.

Apps covered Signup, Login with email, Login with Facebook, Group messaging (send text message, images, videos within the group), P2P (peer to peer) messaging. Push notification messaging for offline user's functionalities.

Project developed on Agile Model with bi-weekly sprints.

My Role: Development, Database Design, Leading and guiding team on Other projects for Xpanxion client.

#2. MiFitJournal mobile application (iOS,Android)	
Client Name:	MiFitJournal App
Team Size:	10
Duration:	7 Months (Nov 2015 - May 2016)
Technologies:	C#.Net, Xamarin android,Xamarin iOS,MaongoDB

**Description:** MyFitJournal is social media Lifestyle app for healthy lifestyle. App allows the user to track diet and exercise through running and walking. User can add food for breakfast, lunch or dinner, Add Walk or Run activity while sharing them with friends on Facebook, twitter and Instagram.

Run Tracking: During and after Run activity, get the key status like distance, pace, and calories burned, as well as an interactive map of your activity with its timeline. For Walk activity we have developed Healthkit like App on Android which keeps a track of steps taken by user during the day, and allows the use to post it online. On iOS we have integrated walk activity with health.

**My Role:** Developing API and Xamarin android application, Team Lead, Scrum meetings with customer. **iTunes link:** 

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/myfitjournal/id1108892377?ls=1&mt=8

Playstore link:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.myfitjournalapp.droid&hl=en

#3. E-Commerce portal application and website	
Client Name:	Gainsaver (www.gainsaver.com)
Team Size:	2
Duration:	July 2015 to Apr 2016
Technologies:	Asp.net, VB.Net, SQL Server 2008



### **Description:**

It is E-Commerce portal application for selling refurbished products. There are two modules: Admin and website. Admin portal maintain following modules:

Website setup, Communication, Sales and Services, Orders, Product and Service, Website tools, Report, Accounting, Marketing. Integration with payment gateways (Affirm) and 3<sup>rd</sup> party customer review applications (Yotpo). Site optimized for SEO to appear in first 10 links on google search

**My Role:** Complete coordination with customer, Development, Database Design, Managing the local team, Code Review, Evaluating customer requirements and suggesting implementations during Scrum Calls.

Customers website: <a href="https://www.gainsaver.com/">https://www.gainsaver.com/</a>

#4. Flaime Mobile Application (iOS,Android)	
Client Name:	Flaime (www.flaime.co)
Team Size:	4
Duration:	Mar 2014 to July 2015
Technologies:	Xamarin, C#, .NET WebAPI 2, MongoDB,

**Description:** Flaime is a social discovery application that facilitates communication between mutually interested users. The app allows users to chat with their matches, change own profile. post like and comment on it. App is realised on iOS and Android store.

**My Role:** Coordination with Business uses during Scrum Calls, Development, Database Design, bug fixing, Manual Testing, develop and maintain webapi, lead team technically on Xamarin.

## iTunes link:

### Playstore link:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.flaime.droid&hl=en

#5. File and Task Management Portal	
Client Name:	Thinkspider
Team Size:	3
Duration:	Apr 2014 – Sept-2014
Technologies:	HTML 5, bootstrap, angularJs, REST Web api .NET, SQL Server 2008 R2

## **Description:**

It is project related to file management and task management. It has Hierarchy management for roles and security. In this project there are four modules document, task, control, chat.

- 1) Document module user can upload file and store it on our personal space or shared space for user associate department.
- 2) Task module –user can create task with associated task team members. For every task there are four roles owner, contributor, reviewer, approval.

The process of task is owner creates task and add contributor for this task, reviewer review this task and review it and update status as reviewed. After reviewed task goes for approval. Approver approves this task.

- 3) Chat Module In this module member can chat with task members or outside members.
- 4) Control module In this module manage all master data and user management.

# My Role:

- 1) Design the system flow.
- 2) Assign task to developer via Jira.
- 3) Manage status meeting for development status every day and scrum meeting every weekend.
- 4) Resolving issue and bugs.



#6. Miutility Portal	
Client Name:	MiLogik
Team Size:	10
Duration:	Jan 2013 – Apr-2014
Technologies:	Orchard CMS 1.6, C#, ASP.Net with Razor, SQL Server 2008 R2, SOAP UI
Payment Gateway	Fiserv, Govolution's Velocity Payment System

### Description:

This is the Web Content management system application. This application is created for clients of MiLogik "People Natural Gas" and "Howard county". PNG and HC are Service provider companies which provide the different facilities like Gas, Electricity, and Water. Through this application user can register, check their gas, electricity, and water consumption and pay the bill online.

- In Admin module we have done the following:
- 1) Manage the user, role, and permissions.
- 2) Ability to change the content of the UI with an available widget.
- 3) Ability to create and change email template content.

## My Role:

- 1) To work on bill module.
- 2) Creating a wrapper class to communicate with miutility portal UI interaction.
- 3) Create a payment gateway interface using web services to pay online payment.

#7. HIS	
Client Name:	DesignTech Systems
Team Size:	15-20
Duration:	Aug 2011 - Jan 2013
Technologies:	Windows Forms, VB.NET, Crystal Reports, SQL Server 2008

### Description

Hospital Management Information System provides a secure, robust environment for transactions across all departments of the hospital and remote access of patient medical records for physicians and nurses. Modules covered are enterprise management, patient management, material management, Laboratory Information, Surgical management, Financial Management, Radiology, Support Services, interfaces, Management Information System.

## My Role:

Creating CSLA Framework base objects. Like Editable Root, List object, Editable Root Collection Object and Working with UI (User interface), Creating stored procedures, Web Services, and WCF Services.

#8. Payroll	
Client Name:	Deccan Mechanical
Team Size:	3
Duration:	Sep. 2009 - July 2011



Technologies: ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server 2008, JQuery, CSS

## **Description:**

The system kept track of attendance of the employees, allocation of leaves as per designation, leaves taken by the employees, salary processing, Advance given to the employee. The System is designed to print various reports like monthly Report, PF Reports and ESI Reports. The system has a utility to delete the Attendance Muster.

#### Mv Role:

Development, Database Design, bug fixing, Manual Testing

#9. ERP	
Client Name:	Deccan Mechanical
Team Size:	5
Duration:	Sep. 2007 – June 2010
Technologies:	Visual Basic 6.0, SQL Server 2008, Crystal Report

## **Description:**

We have developed modules for Marking, Purchase, Store, Sales and Account Module.

### My Role:

Development, Database Design, bug fixing, Manual Testing